#### Lara Hocheiser

Brooklyn, NY 11238 | 774-353-6591 | laraellenh@gmail.com

Github | Blog | Website

# **FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Experienced in Ruby on Rails back-end, and ReactJS front-end, with a background in entrepreneurship, facilitation & technical writing. Possess communication and collaboration skills that serve client and company, leading to company wellbeing and growth. Published nonfiction (technical) book author, prolific blogger, fluent in Spanish, 20 years in education. Yoga and mindfulness subject matter expert.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby, Rails, SQL, JavaScript, ReactJS with proven ability to learn new languages and frameworks quickly.

Technologies and applications: Trello, Slack, Asana, Google suite, Microsoft suite, Squarespace, Shopify, QuickBooks, Stripe

# **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# Kanye Rest API Project- phase 1 Flatiron

In this app, the user can plan a game to guess whether Donald Trump or Kanye West said a quote.

- In the group project, we were learning to use HTML, JS, and CSS in conjunction to create a single page web app (front-end only)
- Collaborated with 2 team members to build a one-page web app using React which includes 3 event listeners
- Used Vanilla JavaScript, CSS, and HTML to build a functional single page web app
- Fetched data from the Kayne Rest API to produce random quotes

## Humans Helping Humans - phase 2 Flatiron -Demo

In this React multi-page webapp, our group built a site using a db.json file in addition to using an external API to produce science-based facts for people to optimize their health

- Built a functional multi-page web app using React 17 frontend
- Collaborated with 2 team members, delegating jobs between CSS, React.js, and HTML resulting in a passing grade
- Used React-Router-Dom to build a multi-page web app for the first time

# Reading List App - phase 5 Flatiron | Demo

This web app has a Ruby on Rails back end and React. JS front end. Using the public library API, you can see 50 Kurt Vonnegut book titles and add to your reading list, make notes about books, and mark them as read

- Fetched from the public library API using Ruby using a complex data set
- Created a many-to-many relationship on Rails, where a user has many favorites books and books through favorite books. Favorite books have many users through books.
- Created a full stack, multi-page web app with multiple URL paths, a login, authentication, cookies, sessions, homepage, and favorites
- Wrote full CRUD for the user's reading list objects
- Hit MVP and qualified to graduate the full-stack course

### **EXPERIENCE**

Flow and Grow Kids Yoga

Brooklyn, NY 09/2012 - 2022

Founder

- Designed, facilitated professional development training to 500 + professionals in the field of children's yoga and mindfulness
- School programming 50+ clients, curriculum development, e-commerce, sales, billing, customer service, hiring, team building
- Author of 2 nonfiction mindfulness books through major publisher 2021
- Presented at the National Kids Yoga Conference 2020/2021
- Member of Yoga Alliance YACEP, E-RYT, RCYT, RCYS 2012-present, exceeding standards

## Gaia

Staff writer

Contributed articles as a yoga and mindfulness subject matter expert

05/2015-50/2018

Online

**Pine Village Preschool** 

Newton, MA 07/2008 - 07/2011

Lead Spanish Immersion Teacher Taught in Spanish Immersion preschool, designed and implemented curriculum

# **EDUCATION**

# Flatiron School

NY. NY

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

12/ 2021 - 4/2022

**Roanoke College** Cum Laude, B.A. in Spanish Language and Sociology Salem, VA

05/2008